<MESHLAB_FILTER_INTERFACE mfiVersion="2.0">
<PLUGIN pluginName="FilterScreenedPoissonPlugin" pluginAuthor="Paolo Cignoni" pluginEmail="paolo.cignoni@isti.cnr.it">
<FILTER filterFunction="screenedPoissonSurfaceReconstruction" filterName="Screened Poisson Surf. Reconstruction" filterPre="MM_NONE" filterRasterArity="SingleRaster" filterClass="Smoothing | Remeshing" filterPost="MM_FACENORMAL | MM_VERTCOORD | MM_VERTNORMAL" filterArity="SingleMesh" filterIsInterruptible="true">
<FILTER_HELP><![CDATA[Screened Poisson Surface Reconstruction. .]]></FILTER_HELP>
<FILTER_JSCODE><![CDATA[]]></FILTER_JSCODE>

   <PARAM parName="depth" parIsImportant="true" parType="Int" parDefault="8">
   <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[This integer is the maximum depth of the tree that will be used for surface reconstruction.
   Running at depth d corresponds to solving on a voxel grid whose resolution is no larger than 2^d x 2^d x 2^d.
   Note that since the reconstructor adapts the octree to the sampling density, the specified reconstruction depth
   is only an upper bound.
   The default value for this parameter is 8.]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <EDIT_GUI guiLabel="Reconstruction Depth"/>
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="fullDepth" parType="Int" parIsImportant="true" parDefault="5">
   <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[This integer specifies the depth beyond depth the octree will be adapted. At coarser depths,
   the octree will be complete, containing all 2^d x 2^d x 2^d nodes.
   The default value for this parameter is 5.]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <EDIT_GUI guiLabel="Adaptive Octree Depth"/>
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="voxelDepth" parType="Int" parIsImportant="true"  parDefault="5">
   <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[This integer is the depth of the regular grid over which the implicit function is to be sampled.
   Running at depth d corresponds to sampling on a voxel grid whose resolution is 2^d x 2^d x 2^d.
   The default value for this parameter is the value of the depth parameter]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <EDIT_GUI guiLabel="Voxel Sampling Depth"/>
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="cgDepth" parType="Int" parIsImportant="true" parDefault="0">
   <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[This integer is the depth up to which a conjugate-gradients solver will be used to solve the
   linear system. Beyond this depth Gauss-Seidel relaxation will be used.
   The default value for this parameter is 0.]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <EDIT_GUI guiLabel="Conjugate Gradients Depth"/>
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="scale" parIsImportant="true" parType="Real" parDefault="1.1">
   <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[This floating point value specifies the ratio between the diameter of the cube used for
   reconstruction and the diameter of the samples' bounding cube.
   The default value is 1.1.]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <EDIT_GUI guiLabel="Scale Factor" />
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="samplesPerNode" parType="Real" parIsImportant="true" parDefault="1">
   <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[This floating point value specifies the minimum number of sample points that should fall
   within an octree node as the octree construction is adapted to sampling density. For noise-free samples, small values
   in the range [1.0 - 5.0] can be used. For more noisy samples, larger values in the range [15.0 - 20.0] may be needed
   to provide a smoother, noise-reduced, reconstruction.
   The default value is 1.0.]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <EDIT_GUI guiLabel="Minimum Number of Samples"/>
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="pointWeight" parType="Real" parIsImportant="true" parDefault="4">
      <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[This floating point value specifies the importants that interpolation of the point samples
      is given in the formulation of the screened Poisson equation.
      The results of the original (unscreened) Poisson Reconstruction can be obtained by setting this value to 0.
      The default value for this parameter is 4.]]></PARAM_HELP>
      <EDIT_GUI guiLabel="Interpolation Weight"/>
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="iters" parType="Int" parIsImportant="true" parDefault="8">
     <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[This integer value specifies the number of Gauss-Seidel relaxations to be performed at each
     level of the hiearchy.
     The default value for this parameter is 8.]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <EDIT_GUI guiLabel="Gauss-Seidel Relaxations"/>
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="confidence" parIsImportant="true" parType="Boolean" parDefault="false">
   <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[Enabling this flag tells the reconstructor to use the size of the normals as confidence
   information. When the flag is not enabled, all normals are normalized to have unit-length prior
   to reconstruction.]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <CHECKBOX_GUI guiLabel="Confidence Flag"/>
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="nWeights" parIsImportant="true" parType="Boolean" parDefault="false">
   <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[Enabling this flag tells the reconstructor to use the size of the normals to modulate the
   interpolation weights. When the flag is not enabled, all points are given the same weight.]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <CHECKBOX_GUI guiLabel="Weight Flat"/>
   </PARAM>
   <PARAM parName="density" parIsImportant="true" parType="Boolean" parDefault="false">
   <PARAM_HELP><![CDATA[Enabling this flag tells the reconstructor to output the estimated depth values of the
   iso-surface vertices.]]></PARAM_HELP>
   <CHECKBOX_GUI guiLabel="Density Flag"/>
   </PARAM>
  </FILTER>
  </PLUGIN>
  </MESHLAB_FILTER_INTERFACE>
